<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutrients on Health for you life</title>
    <link>https://a8king.com/categories/nutrients/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutrients on Health for you life</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a8king.com/categories/nutrients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VitaminC</title>
      <link>https://a8king.com/post/VitaminC.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a8king.com/post/VitaminC.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin C – Biological Functions, Clinical Benefits, and Safety Considerations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-introduction&#34;&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ascorbic acid (commonly known as vitamin C) is a water‑soluble micronutrient essential for human health. Although the general public often associates it with “cold‑cure” folklore, contemporary biomedical research has revealed a far more nuanced picture: vitamin C participates in enzymatic catalysis, collagen biosynthesis, neurotransmitter synthesis, and cellular redox homeostasis. This review synthesizes current evidence on its physiological roles, therapeutic potential, and safety profile, providing an academically rigorous foundation suitable for dissemination to both scientific and lay audiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin_B1</title>
      <link>https://a8king.com/post/vitamin_b1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 15:47:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a8king.com/post/vitamin_b1.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vitamin B₁ (Thiamine): Clinical Significance, Physiological Roles, and Clinical Manifestations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-introduction&#34;&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thiamine (vitamin B₁) is a water‑soluble micronutrient that plays a pivotal role in cellular energy metabolism and neural function. Because it functions as an essential cofactor for several key enzymes involved in carbohydrate oxidation, its deficiency can precipitate a spectrum of clinical syndromes ranging from subtle neurocognitive disturbances to life‑threatening organ failure. This review synthesizes current evidence on the biochemical mechanisms underlying thiamine’s actions, delineates the hallmark symptoms associated with deficiency, and highlights practical considerations for prevention and management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
